A Guide to the Melville DeLancey Landon ("Eli Perkins") Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #7844
Melville DeLancey Landon ("Eli Perkins") Collection 1873-1895
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
7844
ca. 11 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Deposit [1963 Dec 17] 1965 Feb 17
Item Listing
- Manuscript
  - Brief description of a "bore", n. d.; AMsS, 1 p.
- Letters
  - Melville DeLancey Landon to "My Dear Arthur", 1873 Dec 1; AMsS, 1 p.
    [Encourages Arthur in his resolve to stop drinking.]
  - Melville DeLancey Landon to "My dear Eben", [1876?] Nov 30; ALS, 1 p.
    [Sends a recipe for a hot rum drink; mentions Rev Mr. Talmodge; on verso is the top half of a page of a letter, dated 1878 Oct 26, to Melville DeLancey Landon regarding a collection of autographs and autographed letters of distinguished Americans since the Revolution.]
  - Melville DeLancey Landon to Samuel Sidney McClure, 1892 May 10; ALS, 1 p.
    [Discusses columns he will write about women in the Orient for the "Woman's Page" of McClure's syndicate; attached clipping tells of Melville DeLancey Landon's upcoming trip to the Orient; mentions Mrs. Pratt, Buddhism, Shintoism, Christianity.] (with newspaper article pasted on)
  - Melville DeLancey Landon to Charles F. Wingate, 1893 Apr 17; ALS, 1 p.
    [Mentions his wife's sending $100 for a share of Sullivan County Club and a lot; says that, since he will do much for the club, he wants Mr. Wingate to take good care of him by picking out a good lot for him; mentions a trip to Oregon; mentions Ik Marvel; attached clipping discusses literature paying well in America, cites Mark Twain and Eli Perkins as examples.]
  - Melville Delancey Landon to Samuel Sidney McClure, [1895] Apr 25; ALS, 2 p.
    [Discusses writing a little book that "could let daylight through Coin;" says his India, Japan, and China experience with free coinage should help him; mentions upcoming lecture through the 29th; wishes for a meeting with McClure (as possible publisher for the book) on Tuesday, April 30; mentions Mr. Dana.]
  - Melville Delancey Landon to General Ulysses S. Grant, [n. y.] May 4; ALS, 1 p.
    [Discusses taking "care of Greeley in this direction;" mentions Greeley's "splendid character for satire;" mentions Thomas Nast. ]
- Photographs
  - Portrait of Melville Delancey Landon, with reproduction of pencil sketch of him on verso, n.d., ca. 1893; Photo
  - Full face portrait of Melville Delancey Landon, Photo
- Miscellaneous
  - Humorous "Season Ticket" to "Eli Perkins" Lectures, n. d.; Ticket
    ["Admit the Bearer... anywhere in the world, for years and years."]